Guide to the Sally Belfrage Papers TAM.189
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Writings, 1845-2000
  - Subseries III:F: Transcript Folders/ by name., 1980-1990
    - Spence, Gusty (With 'John McM.'), ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Stewart, Kathleen, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Supergrasses Program, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "Tony", ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Tyrie, Andy, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Tyrie, Hester (and Andy), ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Women's Information Group Meeting, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Misc. Transcripts by Number, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Clippings, etc about Belfast, 1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Misc Collected quotes, for "The Crack", ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Statistics (and clippings) on Northern Ireland for "The Crack", 1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Charabeth Theater Co.-- Programs, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Communist Party of Ireland: "Unity," Literature, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Community Education in N. Ireland: General Info, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Community Education in N. Ireland: Articles/Lectures by P. Murphy, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Community Education in N. Ireland: Info on primary school closings, 1983-1985 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Corrymeera/ N. Ireland Community Study Group: General info/notes, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Irish Republican Army: Report by the British House of Lords; Dec-84, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - New Ireland Forum: Articles about, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - New Ireland Group: Position Papers (John Robb, Chairman), ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Sinn Fein & I.R.A.: Clippings, ca.1980-1990 (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Sinn Fein & I.R.A: Pamphlets, etc., ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Supergrasses- Court Transcripts and Witness Depositions, various cases, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Supergrass System: Pamphlets opposing, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Women in Ireland: Info on Abortion and Birth Control, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Women in Ireland: Info on Economic Status, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Women in Ireland: Info on General issues, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Women in Ireland: Info on Health Fair, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Women in Ireland: Info on Rape and Abuse laws, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Women in Ireland: "Women and Social Policy" for the New Ireland Forum, ca.1980-1990 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Workers Party of Ireland: Literature, 1983-1984 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Subseries III:G: Un-American Activities, 1983-2000
    - Letter from Jo Martin about 1950's, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Notes and Clippings, 1987-1993 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Notebook(with papers from inside), ca.1992 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Misc. Notes, letters, and clippings, 1987-1992 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Misc. drafts etc on NY and London in the 1950's, ca.1990-2000 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Notes from Faith Evans, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Draft: Prologue- Chapter Five, ca.1992 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Draft: Chapters Six-Ten, ca.1992 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Draft: Chapter Eleven- Epilogue, ca.1992 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Reviews, Publicity, and Book Covers, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Subseries III:H: Writings by others, 1939-2000
    - Brandt, Savita (Judith): Manuscript "Before During and After", undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Brandt, Savita (Judith): Manuscript "Mirrors" Parts I-IV, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Brandt, Savita (Judith): Manuscript "Mirrors" Parts V-VIII, undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Misc Papers included in Savita Brandt's Manuscript "Mirrors", ca.1990-2000 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Cook, Lindsay: Manuscript "Intifada Days" - First Half, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Cook, Lindsay: Manuscript "Intifada Days" - Second Half, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Howard" (last name illegible): Article in Spanish on Philosophy, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Manheimer, Josh: Two short story manuscripts, 1980, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Marquand, John P. Jr: Manuscript (possibly memoir), undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Martin, Josephine: Two medical papers (about child psychology), 1965, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Martin (no last name): "To Sally From Martin," an essay about Jews, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Pomerance, Leon: Oral history, interviewed by John Hyslop, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Sonnenberg, Ben: "Mole Wedding" A Play, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Information on Israel/Palestinian Peace Process, etc, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - "Hate, and a Kind of Music" A chapter from a memoir, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Belfrage, Cedric (?) Handwritten Manuscript from folder "Novel", undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Belfrage, Cedric (?) Manuscript-- "Wholesale Price Quotes", undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Belfrage, Cedric (?) Manuscript-- "Henri Quancard", undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Belfrage, Cedric (?) Untitled Fragment of Manuscript, ca.1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Castle, Molly: "This is Where We Came In"--Xeroxed Novel, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Political Activities, 1963-1984
  - SB's Article on feminism "Women are Revolting" plus letter and notes regarding it, ca.1963-1969 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Signature ad in Ramparts against Vietnam War, ca.1970 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Shrew magazine- issue compiled by SB's Women's Group, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Vanity Fair on the Women's Movement, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - SB's article on "Action Feminist Group" in Fakenham, England (and Correspondence with Village Voice), 1975 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Women's Liberation Group (in London): Spare Rib article and drafts (collaborative writings), 1978, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Short Piece on Women's Group, and getting older, ca.1980-1985 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Brief Writings by SB on Greenham Common, 1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Article (and draft) for The Nation by SB- on Greenham Common, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Broadsheet "The Greenham Factor" edited by SB, ca.1983 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Business and fund-raising correspondence for "Greenham Factor", 1983-1985 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Drafts, notes, etc. for "Greenham Factor", ca.1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Letters with offers to help for "Greenham Factor", 1983 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Letters regarding Greenham Common, ca.1983 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Letters of Support for "Greenham Factor" (incl. Germaine Greer), 1984 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - SB's Notebooks for "Greenham Factor", 1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - SB's Notes etc. re Greenham Common, ca.1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Orders for "Greenham Factor", 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Quotes for "Greenham Factor", ca.1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Seeger, Peggy: Correspondence re: Greenham Common, etc., 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Transcripts of Interviews about Greenham Common, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Transcripts/Statements by Women Peace Activists about Greenham, ca.1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Chronology and Directory for Greenham Common/ Women's Peace Movement, ca.1984 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Clippings regarding Greenham Common, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - European Nuclear Disarmament ('END') Information & Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Literature on Greenham Common / Women's Peace Movement, ca.1981-1984 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Magazines (Committee for Nuclear Disarmament, Observer, Marxism Today) on Greenham Common, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets and Newsletters on Greenham Common, ca.1982-1984 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Papers on Non-violence and Women, by Rosalie Bertell and James D. Hunt, 1976, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Play:"The Gates of Greenham" by "T.B.", ca.1984 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Songs and other original material out of Greenham Common, ca.1982-1984 (Box 36, Folder 15)
- Series V: Government Files, 1978-1984
  - FBI files: SB's Correspondence with Government, lawyers, etc, 1978-1995 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - SB's notes on process of getting FBI files, ca.1979-1993 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - FBI files on Mary Belfrage (Molly Castle) (released 1989), ca.1989 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - CIA files on SB, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - FBI files on SB- Misc- Folder A, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - FBI files on SB- Misc- Folder B, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - FBI files on SB- Cross References- Folder C, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Passport Office files on SB, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - State Department files on SB, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Army Department files on Cedric Belfrage, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 1, part A, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 1, part B, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 2 (includes HUAC testimony), undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 3, undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 4, part A, undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 4, part B, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 5-6, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 7, part A, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 7, part B, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: '100-34463' Vol. 8 and 'A', undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage, from a separate request (released 1996), undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - FBI files on Cedric Belfrage: 'Consultations with other government agencies', undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Justice Department files on Cedric Belfrage, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - State Department files on Cedric Belfrage, undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Government files on Cedric (and Mary) Belfrage, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 8 (?), undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 118, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 236, undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 248, undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 292, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 366, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 440, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 467, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 675, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 810, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Serials 939, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Misc. Unnumbered files (folder A), undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - FBI files on Gregory and Helen Silvermaster: 65-56402 Misc. Unnumbered files (folder B), undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Photographs and Audiovisual Material, 1910s-1994
  - Sally's Family: Older Generation, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Cedric Belfrage, circa 1910s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Cedric Belfrage (Oversize), 1930s (Box Shared Tamiment OS009, Folder 1)
  - Molly Castle and Co., circa 1918-1980s (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Molly Castle (Oversize), 1920s-1940s (Box Shared Tamiment OS009, Folder 2)
  - Nick Belfrage, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Family (Including Bernard and Lee Pomerance, Eve and Moby Pomerance, and Jo Martin), 1940s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - 7777 Firenze Ave, CA (I) (includes Shirley Temple), circa 1936-1944 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - 7777 Firenze Ave, CA (II) (Includes Sally Belfrage as an Infant), 1936 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - 7777 Firenze Ave, CA (III) (Sally Belfrage Ages 1 to 5), 1936-1941 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - 500 Kappock Ave and 210 65th Street, NYC, 1951-1955 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - 16 Talbot Square, London, circa 1955-1965 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - 16 Talbot Square, London, circa 1956-1960 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Burgess and McLean (Moscow), late 1950s (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - China, American Youth Delegation, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - "Memory of the Heart" Film Stills, circa 1957 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Moscow (I) (Includes Nikolai Khrushchev), 1957-1958 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Moscow (II) (Friends), 1957-1958 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Middle East (I) (Includes King Hussein), 1959 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Middle East (II), 1959 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Middle East (III) (Jerusalem), 1959 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Ben Sonnenberg and Sally (Malaga, Spain), 1961 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Mexico and Cuba, circa 1962 (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - South (Georgia and North Carolina), 1963 (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Assorted Photos of the 1980s (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Early Spring 1985 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Spring 1985 (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - May-June 1985, May 1985 - Jun 1985 (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Belfast, Jul 1985 (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Belfast (Marching), Jul 1985 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - McDowell, Aug 1985 (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Autumn 1985 (Ireland) (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - October 1985 (London), Oct 1985 (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Tel Aviv, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - Photographs from Sally's Wall, 1977-1990 (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - Portraits of Sally Belfrage, 1940s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - Portraits of Sally Belfrage (Oversize), circa 1939-1950s (Box Shared Tamiment OS009, Folder 3)
  - Loose Photos, 1970s-1990s (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - China (I), [1957] (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - China (II), [1957] (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - China (III), [1957] (Box 42, Folder 38)
  - China (IV), [1957] (Box 42, Folder 39)
  - China (V), [1957] (Box 42, Folder 40)
  - Slides, undated (Box 42, Folder 41)
  - Memorial for Sally Belfrage VHS Tapes, June 8, 1994; 2 videocassettes
  - Symphony Space VHS Tapes, June 27, 1994; 5 videocassettes
  - Unlabeled VHS Tapes, undated; 2 videocassettes
  - Symphony Space Film Reels, June 27, 1994; 8 Reels
  - Power, Marg audiorecording, undated (Box 43, Cassette 1)
  - G, Emma audiorecording, undated (Box 43, Cassette 2)
  - Conference on Civil Rights Studies Session 3-5, 1989 (Box 43, Cassette 5, Cassette 4, Cassette 3)
  - "The White Integrationalists" a documentary by Colin D. Edwards audiorecording, 1965 (Box 43, Reel 1)
- Series VII: Restricted Items
  Scope and Contents
  Born digital items include: Floppy Disk, 3½" - 20
  Floppy Disk, 5¼" - 10
  Zip Disk 100mb - 1
  Most labeled Correspondence, Un-American Activities notes, and "computer files"
  Access to series VII is restricted until 2021.
  - Selected files removed from boxes 4 and 11 which are closed until 2021, 1903-1994 (Box 44)
  - Selected files removed from boxes 4 and 11 which are closed until 2021, 1903-1994 (Box 41)
  - Computer Files (floppy disks and zip disk) (Box 40)